孩子们 2013年春天
Kids, by the spring of 2013,
莉莉和马修的小日子过得很不错
Lily and Marshall had life figured out;
莉莉作为船长大人的艺术品顾问逐渐开始崭露头角
Lily was making a name as the art consultant for The Captain,
马修是个明星环保律师
Marshall was a superstar environmental lawyer
家庭生活如同上过油的机器一般井井有条
and home life was a well-oiled machine.
紧接着
And then...
事情就变了
something changed.
船长大人 您要见我吗
Captain, you wanted to see me?
船长大人 在吗
Captain? Hello?
请求登船许可
Permission to come aboard?
批准
Granted.
莉莉 有一点小事 我准备搬到罗马
Lily, small order of business. I'm moving to Rome
我希望你能跟我一起去
and I'd like you to come with me.
现在走起
Carry on.
什么 那也太棒了
What?! That-That-That's amazing,
只是 我不知道能否就这样离开这生我养我的地方
but I-I don't know if I can just uproot my life.
就去一年而已 走起
It's only for a year. Carry on.
可我都结婚了 还有个孩子
But I'm married and we have a baby
Shake Shack是美国街边卖零食的连锁店
而且我们那边刚开了一家奶昔小站
and they just opened a Shake Shack on our block
而且从来都不用排队
and there's never a line!
我明白这决定事关重大
I understand it's a big decision.
给你足够时间慢慢考虑
Take all the time you need.
只要在今天结束之前告诉我就行
Just let me know by the end of the day.
顺便 我在置办行李方面需要你的一些建议
Also, I need your advice on purchasing some luggage.
Carry on有手提的 走起等多重意思
-什么样的?  -手提的
-What kind? -Carry on.
老爸\N　　　  　　 老妈\N　　 　　 浪漫史\N　　  　　　　第八季  第二十一集\N
S08E21 Romeward Bound
翻译: @Big-Fudge @Mr_Gao703 @卟哒哒伽马\N@麟礡 @阿狸小H\N校对: @我叫肉鸭鸭 @晒小花
压制: @Big-Fudge\N统筹+后期: @我叫肉鸭鸭 @晒小花
HIMYM字幕组 倾情奉献
玩得挺开心的 我先走了
Well, this has been fun. I should go.
可你简直是刚过来啊
But you literally just got here.
我才没有"简直是"刚过来
I didn't "Literally" Just get here.
我真心痛恨总有人老是滥用那个词
I hate when people misuse that word.
详见S03E08 Robin因滥用这个词被众人吐槽
我也是 可你真的简直是刚刚过来
So do I. But you literally just got here.
嘿 泰德
Hey, Ted.
玩得挺开心的 我先走了
Well, this has been fun. I should go.
好吧 行 现在我真的要走了
Okay, fine, now I'm leaving.
人们到底为什么要来酒吧
Why do people go to a bar, anyway?
喝上两杯啤酒 扒下女人裤子
To get your drink on and some girl's pants off.
这两样我在家都能办到
I can do both at home.
你看什么呢
What are you looking at?
那个穿大衣的妹子
The girl in the big coat?
我俩之前一起上过同一节瑜伽课
We were in the same yoga class together.
你有没有觉得 有些时候你遇见一个姑娘
You know how sometimes you'll meet a girl and there'll be
她不经意间表现出的一点点特质
that one bewitching little detail that'll make you
就能让你一瞬间爱上她
fall in love with her instantly?
比如 鼻子上的小雀斑
You know, a little freckle on the nose,
轻快活泼的笑声
the-the lilt of her laugh,
还有她说出某个词时的那种音调
the way she pronounces a certain word or phrase?
是啊 当然了
Sure, totally.
好吧 对于这个姑娘来说
Well, in this girl's case,
她那一点点的特质就是
the bewitching little detail is the fact
她有一个"八可思议"的火爆身材
that she has just a "Redonkulous" Body.
八可思议
Redonkulous?
Redonkulous!
我只听过你用"八可思议"这个词来形容
I've only heard you use "Redonkulous" To describe
《碟中谍4: 幽灵协议》
Mission Impossible: Ghost Protocol.
巴尼 这个姑娘
Barney, this girl has
有着如碟中谍般八可思议的身材
the Mission Impossible: Ghost Protocol of bodies.
碟中谍英文直译为 不可能的任务
哇哦
Whoa.
你就等她把大衣脱下来吧
Just wait till she takes that coat off.
等下 你刚刚都打算走了 不是吗
Oh, wait, sorry, you were just about to leave, right?
就是 这酒钱我花都花了
I mean, I've already paid for this drink.
伙计们 船长大人刚提了一件很有意思的事
Guys, The Captain just made me a very interesting offer.
哎呦 我们可算知道他为什么雇你了
Finally, we get around to the real reason he hired you.
你就答应他你会拍的 而且一定要用三脚架
Just promise you film it, and please use a tripod.
没有防抖毫无艺术感可言
There's nothing artistic about shaky-cam.
那样看起来软塌塌的
It just looks sloppy.
他想让我跟他去罗马待上一年 帮他买入艺术品
He wants me to move to Rome for a year to buy art for him.
哇 真的吗
Whoa! Seriously?
-那是你想要做的事情吗  -开玩笑吧你
-Is that something you want to do? -Are you kidding?
我一直以来都想在国外生活
I've always wanted to live abroad!
我上大学时 在巴黎度过的夏天令人茅塞顿开
My summer in Paris, back in college, was so enlightening:
艺术啊 历史啊 还有免费的奶酪啊
the art, the history, the free cheese
穿件低胸装就能吃到
just for wearing a low-cut top.
马修对于你们搬家是什么态度
Well, how does Marshall feel about moving?
我还没跟他说呢
I haven't told him yet.
他真的很喜欢在这里的工作
He really loves his job here.
是啊 可他也同样喜欢意大利
Yeah, but he also loves Italy!
他在大学里学了一周的意大利语课
He took a week of Italian in college,
而且他放弃这门课的唯一原因是
and the only reason he dropped it was
因为他对不能飘飘欲仙很反感
'cause he had a conflict... with being not stoned.
可他到现在还记得怎么说这句话
But he still knows how to say the phrase,
"拜托 老兄 别独占所有洋葱圈"
"Come on, bro, don't Bogart all the Funyuns."
好吧 我这就给他打电话
All right, I'm gonna call him.
嘿 宝贝
Hey, baby.
嘿 宝贝 现在没法讲话
Hey, baby, I can't talk right now.
忙着大案子呢 拜
I'm working on a big case. Bye.
那个时候莉莉突然明白
And that's when Lily realized
搬到罗马去意味着什么
what moving to Rome would really mean.
季诺•卡维里尼 下来参赛吧
不知不觉之间
And before you know it...
他的生活就变成一部充满焦虑感的
...his life turns into an angsty,
意大利存在主义黑白电影
existential black-and-white Italian movie.
正是如此
Exactly.
\N你是做什么的
我以前是个律师
I used to be a lawyer.
\N你现在做什么呢
我不知道了
I don't know anymore.
\N咱俩为什么不搬到明尼苏达
\N我好学习你妈妈的菜谱
\N给你做砂锅火腿
不好意思 我暂停一下
I'm sorry. I got to hit pause for a second.
这里怎么会这么热
Why is it so hot in here?
噢 是的 当你在一刻不停 喋喋不休于
Oh, right. While you were blabbering on and on
你那堆什么乱七八糟的生活危机的时候
about your whole life crisis or whatever,
我偷偷给了卡尔100刀 好让他把暖气开大
I slipped Carl a hundred to turn the heat up in here.
什么 为什么呢
What? Why?
因为她还穿着那件肥得要死的大衣
Because she is still in the big puffy coat!
巴尼 你现在算是唱的哪出啊
Barney, what are you doing?
我要让她脱掉那件大衣
I'm trying her out of that coat,
我唱的就是这出
that's what I'm doing!
我在以热攻辣
I'm fighting hotness with hotness!
你都订婚了
You're engaged.
好吧 莉莉 很明显你好像忘了点啥事
Okay, Lily, clearly you're forgetting something.
是啊 我跟地球上最棒的女孩订婚了
Yes, I'm engaged to the coolest girl on Earth.
我这只不过是看看而已 又不碰她
This is about looking, not touching.
罗宾明白我有一对球球是她不能用领带
Robin understands there is one set of balls she can't tie up
系起来 用乒乓球拍轻击之的
with a necktie and lightly hit with a Ping-Pong paddle.
就是这对眼球
These balls.
好了 我要打电话给船长
Okay, I'm gonna call The Captain,
把这档子事定下来
get this over with.
啊嗬
Ahoy.
你好 船长
Hello, Captain?
莉莉 我希望你这通电话打来不是
Lily, I hope you're not calling
一叉子把咱们去罗马的计划给毙了的
to harpoon our big move to Rome.
谢谢你 但我不能让我的丈夫放弃他的事业
Thank you, but I can't ask my husband to abandon his career.
你想要我试着去说服他吗
Would you like me to try and convince him?
我很会当说客的
I'm very persuasive.
不好意思 船已经起航
I'm sorry, the ship has sailed.
什么意思
What's that mean?
额 你懂的 "船已经起航"
Well, you know, "The ship has sailed"?
意思就是事情已经尘埃落定 不可改变
That it's over and there's nothing you can do?
真是奇怪的表达呢 唔
What a peculiar expression. Hmm.
好吧 谢谢你辛苦的工作 莉莉
Well, thanks for all your hard work, Lily.
我从不擅长做道别 所以...
I've never been good at good-byes, so...
好吧 就这样结束了
Well, that's that.
我梦想的艺术顾问这工作就这么结束了
My dream job as an art consultant is over.
而可悲的部分是...
And the sad part...
好了 我得打断你一下 莉莉
Okay, I gotta stop you right there, Lily,
因为除非我弄错了 准备好了绅士们
'cause unless I'm mistaken, lock and load gentlemen.
围巾 不是吧 别穿啊 脱啊
A scarf?! No, don't put on, take off!
够了 你都开始流口水了
Okay, you're starting to drool.
太猥琐了
I'm calling creepy.
莉莉 还好啦
Lily, it's fine.
这是个纯学术问题
This is purely academic.
这就像在赏鸟
It's-It's like bird-watching.
现在 我只是在观赏一对极品豪...罗宾
And right now, I am watching a double-breasted-- Robin!
robin有知更鸟的意思
等一下 她们认识
Wait-- they know each other?!
哇哦 等等 到底咋回事
Whoa, wait-- what is going on here?
噢 天啊 真的发生了
Oh, my God, it's happening.
就跟我预想的一样
This is just like I imagined.
在泰德的面前 这样我可以当面羞辱他
Right in front of Ted, so I can rub it in his face.
那腰带是我的
The belt is mine!
S03E03中泰德和巴尼打赌 第一个完成3P的将得到腰带
嗨 伙计们 巴尼 你记得莉迪吧
Hi, guys. Barney, you remember Liddy.
是吗
I do?
对 莉比
Yes! Libby.
是莉迪 罗宾雇我的时候我们见过面的
Liddy. We met when Robin hired me.
罗宾雇你了
Robin hired you?
真调皮 好吧
Naughty girl. Okay.
好了 事情应该怎么办呢
Okay, so how's this gonna go down?
你们俩先开始搞 然后我在中途插进来
You two just gonna start, and I'll just jump in?
呃 她是我们的婚礼策划人
Uh, she's our wedding planner.
她当然是婚礼策划人啦
Of course she's the wedding planner!
很高兴再见到你 莉比
Good to see you again, Libby.
莉迪 对
Liddy. Yeah.
嘿 我是泰德 我们 呃 我们之前见过
Hey, I'm Ted. We, uh, we met once before.
噢 对 在瑜伽课上 你好吗
Oh, right, in yoga class. How are you?
她刚跟我讲话了呢
She's talking to me.
我很想呆在这
Well, I would love to stay,
既然现在我算是失业了
but now that I'm unemployed,
我要去给工作中的马修一个惊喜
I think I'll go surprise Marshall at work.
婚礼策划人
Wedding planner.
于是 莉莉去马修那儿探班了
So Lily went to visit Marshall at work,
希望自己不会打扰到什么重要的事情
hoping she wasn't interrupting anything important.
她没有打扰到
She wasn't.
哦 什么情况
Whoa. What is going on?
伯纳德 如果我们把卡片粘在一起
Bernard, if we just glue the cards together...
莉莉 你来这干嘛呀
Lily! What are you doing here?
呃 我给你烤了布朗尼
Well, I baked you brownies
因为我以为你在忙工作
because I thought you were busy working, but...
当你说...
so when you said...
莉莉 嘿 我现在不方便说话
Lily, hey, I can't really talk.
我现在在做一个大项目
I'm working on a big project right now.
实在是个很难完成项目
It's a real house of cards.
这就是你说的"很难完成项目"
Is this the "House of cards" You were talking about?
house of cards双关 卡片屋
我还以为你有个什么大客户呢
I thought you had some big client.
噢 亲爱的 我们已经几个月没客户了
Oh, sweetheart, we haven't had a client here in months.
嗯 布朗尼 不错嘛
Mmm! Brownies! Hey!
到底怎么了 你说几个月
What is going on? What do you mean
都没有客户了是什么意思
you haven't had a client in months?
自从格鲁伯案子之后
Ever since the Gruber case,
我们一落千丈
we lost a lot of business,
大家都走人了 现在就剩我和伯纳德
people got laid off... it's just me and Bernard now.
库茨呢
Where's Cootes?
他穴居在科罗拉多的防空洞
He's holed up in a bomb shelter in Colorado,
拾掇着自己的香草园坐等末日
waiting for the apocalypse and tending to his herb garden.
那么过去的几个月我给你打电话
So all those times I've called you in the past few months,
你说你忙的不得了
when you talked about how busy you were...
那些都是在骗我咯
you were just lying to me?
严格地说 我从没骗过你
Technically, I never lied...
嘿 宝贝
Hey, baby.
嘿 宝贝 我现在不方便说话
Hey, baby, I can't talk right now.
忙着大案子呢 拜
I'm working on a big case. Bye.
这真心是一大箱子啊
That is a big case.
case有箱子和案子两个意思
现在不是时候 莉莉
Bad time, Lily.
我得专心应对客户
I got to focus on the client.
挂了 再见
Gotta go. Bye.
我们说到哪啦
Where were we?
书名 客户
第十九章
Chapter 19.
我现在没法儿聊天 我的台面都铺满了
I can't talk right now; I got a lot on my plate.
好 开吃吧
Well, let's dig in.
要是我们现在开始 午饭之前就能吃完
If we start now, we can be done by lunch.
这会儿没空 莉莉
Now's not a good time, Lily.
这儿没人能腾出手来
We got a lot of balls in the air right now.
好的 把订书机扔给我
Okay, toss me the stapler.
简直不敢相信
Unbelievable.
等下 你告诉我说你就要击垮别人了...
Wait-- when you said you were about to get reamed...
哦 对 那个
Oh, right. That.
有时候 为了找乐子
No, sometimes, for fun,
我们互相扔纸玩
We throw reams of paper at each other.
伯纳德 这会儿不是时候
Bernard! Not a good time!
有点眼色好不好
Read the room!
很抱歉 宝贝 我
I'm sorry, baby, I...
我不想让你目睹我的失败
I didn't want you to see me fail.
该死 你知道你的谎言带来了多严重的后果吗
Damn it! Do you realize what you cost us by lying to me?
船长要搬去罗马
The Captain is moving to Rome,
他邀请我 作为他的艺术顾问与他同行
and he offered to bring me along as his art consultant,
但是我拒绝了 因为我以为你爱你的工作
but I turned it down, because I thought you loved your job.
哦 我滴天啊
Oh, my gosh.
如果我们去意大利
If we lived in Italy,
我就可以整天照顾马尔文
I could just spend my days taking care of Marvin
学做意大利面 看意大利版价格猜猜猜
and trying to make pasta and watching Italian Price Is Right.
简直跟做梦一样
It sounds like a dream!
哦 已经太晚了
Oh, it's too late.
不 没有 莉莉
No, no. Lily,
我现在就去找船长
I'm going to The Captain's right now!
我要亡羊补牢
I'm gonna make this right!
我会让你拿回那份工作的
I'm gonna get you that job!
-不要了 马修  -你会拿回那份工作的
-No, Marshall... -You're getting that job!
你可以写给莉迪•盖茨
You can just make it out to Liddy Gates.
拼写是L-I-D-D-Y
That's L-I-D-D-Y.
L-I 两个D
L-I, two D's...
一对儿D
double D...
请自行脑补内衣尺码
两个D...Y
two D's... -Y.
Y谐音 为什么啊
好了 这是最终的菜单 我们之前讨论过的
Well, here is the final menu, as we discussed,
强调一下
but let me be clear.
你们是老板 我是为你们服务的
You're the boss; I'm here to serve you.
所以如果有你们不想要的东西
So if there's anything you want me to remove,
就直接跟我讲 我立马给你们去掉
just tell me to remove it and it's gone.
你们不想要的我一件不留
I'll remove anything you want.
男人们都在想去掉她的大衣
这听上去很合理
That sounds like a sound policy.
这取决于你 你喜欢什么样的
Up to you, whatever you feel like.
这挺好... 你告诉我这些非常好
That's a good... That's a good thing to know.
没关系 你想去掉什么就去掉什么
That's fine, you can remove whatever you want.
我是认真的 我不会觉得这是冒犯 你们不想要的
I'm serious, and I won't be offended; you want it gone,
男人们还是在想去掉她的大衣
我立马去掉 这是很热吗
I'll take it right off. Is it hot in here?
不算冷 你知道吗
It's not cold. You know what?
是很热 粘粘的 没有... 就好像
It's hot; it's sticky. It's not... It's like
高温瑜珈一样 对吧
Bikram, right?
我们是瑜伽之友
We're yoga buddies.
瑜珈之友啊
Yoga buddies.
好的 你们看看菜单
Well, I'll let you guys read the menu.
-麻烦问下...  -找衣帽架吗×2
-Can you point me to the... -Coat rack?
...洗手间在哪
...restroom?
呃 就在那边
Uh, it's right over there.
但是穿着那么大的大衣尿尿很不方便啊
But it's hard to pee in a giant coat.
好吧 这是怎么了
Okay, what's going on?
你们怎么都这么奇怪
Why are you guys being so weird?
泰德说莉迪的身材八可思议
Ted says that Liddy has a ridonkulous body,
但是现在没办法证实
but there's no way of verifying
因为她就是不脱掉大衣
because she won't take off the coat!
所以这儿的温度才这么高的吗
Is that why it's so hot in here?
你又花钱让卡尔把暖气调高了哈
Did you pay Carl to turn up the heat again?
嗯 没错
Well, yes.
不过我只是好奇
But I was curious.
我想把那件大衣搭到架子上面
I want to get that coat on the rack
rack同时有一对咪咪和架子的意思
好看看大衣里面的那对东西
so I can see the rack that's under the coat.
我的天哪
My God.
我一直在想
I have been wondering
同一件事
the same thing.
我是说 她从来都不脱那件大衣
I mean, she never takes that coat off.
无论她那下面藏了什么
Whatever she's smuggling under there
都得前方高能反应预警
has to be thermonuclear.
我打赌她有破内胸
I bet she has WBDs.
破坏内衣之胸器
Weapons of bra destruction.
谢谢
Thank you.
这就是为什么
This, this is why
你是史上最赞未婚妻 没有之一
you're the coolest fiancee ever.
所以 泰德 你说八可思议...
So, Ted, when you say ridonkulous...
我无法描述
I can't even describe it.
这就跟给盲人描述彩虹一样
It'd be like trying to explain a rainbow to a blind person.
她单身吗
Is she single?
你怎么不约她出来
Why don't you ask her out?
其实 我们第一次见面我差点可以把她约出去了
Actually, I almost did the first time we met,
要不是她脱掉那件大衣的话
before she took off that coat.
沙尘暴
Sandstorm?
均是电影碟中谍4里面的镜头
迪拜 那个帽衫吗
Dubai? That hoodie?
我觉得 简直八可思议
I mean, it's ridonkulous.
哦 我知道 我真想再看一遍
Oh, I know. I so want to see it again.
哟 那下课以后
Well, hey, I mean, maybe after this,
如果你没有其它安排的话
if you're not doing anything.
没问题 也许看完之后
Totally, and maybe later,
我们还能吃些东西
we could get a bite to eat.
就在这跟前有个特别棒的饭店
There's this great place that's super close.
不
No, I...
我... 不
No, I... No.
一下子信息量太大了
It was just too much.
印第安纳•琼斯也不敢直视她的身姿
Indiana Jones wouldn't look at this body.
电影夺宝奇兵男主角
这个身姿足以融化纳粹的脸
This is a body that would melt a Nazi's face.
哦 伙计 让我的脸也化了吧
Oh, man, I want my face to melt.
真可惜马修不在这儿
It's too bad Marshall isn't here.
为什么
Why Marshall?
因为他能很自然的说
'Cause he could just say...
嘿 莉迪
Hey, Liddy,
干嘛不把大衣脱掉呢
why don't you take off that coat?
莉迪就会
And Liddy would be all...
行啊 把上衣也脱掉吗
Sure, should I take my shirt off, too?
不用 只脱大衣就行
No, the coat's probably enough.
而且完全能置身事外
And he'd get away with it.
知道为什么吗 他不臭臭
You know why? No stink.
显然你没和打完篮球的他共乘过出租车
You obviously haven't split a cab with him after basketball.
不是 我不是说
No, I don't mean
"生理上的臭味"
"Physical stink."
我是指信息素方面
I mean the pheromonal stink
当你渴求性交到了可悲的程度
a guy gives off when he's desperate for action
就会散发出这种气息
to a pathetic degree.
比如 泰德
You know, like Ted.
我都发臭了吗
I have stink?
哥们 你都泡臭水里了
Bro, you dipped in stink.
如果莉迪回来 你跟她说
If Liddy came back to the table and you said...
呃 莉迪
Uh, Liddy,
你干嘛不脱掉大衣呢
why don't you, uh, take off that coat?
你还想让我脱大衣
You want me to take my coat off?
倒不如 我撕烂你的脸
How about instead, I take off your face?
嗷
Ow!
嗷哦
Ow, oh!
说真的
Really?
你就非得让她打我一顿
You had to have her beat me up?
还没完呢 泰德
She's not done, Ted.
幽灵协议
Ghost Protocol
电影碟中谍4
没有 那么 好看
wasn't that good!
另一方面 如果是马修
Marshall, on the other hand,
姑娘们看一眼就知道
girls take one look and just know
他已经邂逅了自己的梦中情人
there's a guy who's met the girl of his dreams
想要与其共度余生
and wants to spend the rest of his life
海枯石烂 忠贞不渝
with her and only her.
那你怎么不问她
So why don't you ask her?
什么
Pardon me?
您难道不是
Aren't you
邂逅了
a guy who's met
梦中情人 并想共度余生
the girl of his dreams and wants to spend
海枯石烂 忠贞不渝的人吗
the rest of his life with her and only her?
我当然是啦 宝贝
Of course, baby.
那为什么不能是你叫她脱掉大衣呢
So why don't you ask her to take her coat off?
呃
Um...
而且你从来就没看过幽灵协议
And you never even saw Ghost Protocol.
你们的大日子就要到了
So, the big day's coming up.
感觉怎么样
How are you guys feeling?
我跟备办酒席的人讨论过了
I talked to the caterer,
迷你羊小腿会很美味哦
and the mini lamb shanks are gonna be amazing.
哦 对了
Oh, by the way,
我还联系了花店 那些紫罗兰
I talked to the florist, and the violets
-也会很漂亮哟  -行的 巴尼 你能做到的
-are gonna be gorgeous. -Okay, Barney. You can do this.
说出来就行 说吧
Just say it. Say it.
大的小的都是
...little ones and big ones...
快说
Say it.
嘿 莉迪 你要脱掉大衣吗
Hey, Liddy, do you want to take off your coat?
行啊
Sure.
我做到啦 我向自己和他人证明了
I did it! I proved to myself and everyone else
我根本没有觊觎其他女人
that I have no desire to be with any other woman.
我对其他女人完全免疫了
I am completely immune to every other...
我滴神啊
Holy crap!
这还真的是
And it was, indeed,
八可思议
ridonkulous.
我们能见到这等奇观
And we got to see it, all thanks
全都要感谢这位美女
to this lovely lady right here.
罗宾 感谢你 我现在可以走近任何姑娘
Robin, thanks to you, I can now walk up to any girl
说我想说的任何猥琐又恶心的话
and say whatever creepy, disgusting thing I want
还能完全置身事外
and totally get away with it.
哈
Mm. Man!
我开始喜欢结婚了
I think I'm gonna like being married.
喂
Hello?
啊嗬
Ahoy.
啊嗬 莉莉
Ahoy, Lily.
我刚和你丈夫长谈了一番
I just had a long talk with your husband.
他说服我再次给你去罗马工作的机会
He convinced me to offer you that job in Rome again.
你怎么说
How do you respond?
谢谢 但是我还是拒绝
Thanks, but the answer is still no.
莉莉 你怎么又把这事儿推掉了
Lily, why the hell did you turn that down again.
因为... 我还得去拍新的护照照片
Because I 'd have to get a new passport photo.
我会错过八月份的纽约
And I'd miss out on New York in August.
而且我们那边新开了一家奶昔小站 所以...
And plus they open the shake shack on a block. So...
莉莉 真正的原因是什么
Lily, what's the real reason?
万一我们搬去了罗马
What if we moved to Rome...
什么事这么好笑
What's so funny?
不好意思
I'm sorry.
我不敢相信你花了一千万欧元买这幅画
I can't believe you paid a 10 million euro for this painting.
有什么问题
Why not?
这根本就不是一幅画
Because it's not even a painting.
我就转转盘子 然后调料就沾到画布上了
I spinned my plate, the sughi fell out on a blank canvas.
闻闻 是厕所味儿吧
Smell it. It's like a toilet.
我把你变成了一个 呃
I just make you look uh
大蠢蛋
stupido.
莉莉 你被解雇了
Lily, you're fired.
什么 别啊 这还是一幅很棒的画作啊
What? But no. I-I...it's still a great painting.
我喜欢它表现出的社会结构
I like what it says about the structure in society
以及妇女角色的转变
and the changing worlds of women.
夺门怒驶出
\N你是做什么工作的
我以前是一个艺术顾问
I used to be an art consultant.
\N我老公以前娶过一个艺术顾问
\N他来了
嘿 宝贝儿 是时候给马尔文来一瓶了
Hey baby. It's time for Marvin's bottle.
这都是因为我搞砸了
And it's all because I screwed up and through away
抛弃了如此舒适的纽约生活
a perfectly comfortable life here in New York.
莉莉 你不会搞砸的
Lily, you're not going to screw up.
好了 求别说了
You know what, just please,
别管这事儿了
just leave it alone.
再说了
Besides,
其实我心里知道
deep down, I don't think
马修肯定一点也不想去意大利
Marshall's even excited about Italy.
与此同时 在小意大利区
At that very moment in little Italy.
小意大利 美国大城市中的意大利移民区
泰德:快回家 莉莉又把工作拒绝了
栗子
Marron!
马修外语水平真可观
我太期待我的婚礼了
I can't wait for my wedding day.
我是说 到时候
I mean, there is no way
莉迪肯定不会还穿着那件大衣了 对吧
that Liddy is gonna be wearing that coat, right?
对吧
Right?
巴尼•斯丁森 你愿意
"Barney Stinson, do you hope
让她穿着紧身露背装吗
she wears something slinky and backless?"
我愿意
"I do."
好了 作为你的伴郎 我能说一句吗
Okay, can I just say something as your best man?
小心点
Be careful.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
你只是... 最近表现得不太像一个
You just... you haven't been acting like a guy
马上要结婚的男人 我知道你觉得这没什么
who's about to get married, and I know you think it's okay
因为罗宾真的很赞 但我要告诉你
because Robin's so cool, but I'm telling you,
她没你想象的那么通情达理
she's not as cool as you think she is.
哦 我明白了
Oh, I see.
你知道这点
And you'd know this
是因为你比我更了解罗宾
because you know Robin better than I do.
你比她的未婚夫更了解她想要什么
You know what she appreciates better than her own fiance.
我只是想说
I'm just saying,
如果我在三周以后就要结婚了...
if I was getting married in three weeks...
但三周以后要结婚不是你 泰德
But you're not getting married in three weeks, Ted.
是我
I am.
罗宾要跟我结婚 不是你
Robin's marrying me, not you.
你说的对
You're right.
我没资格说这些
Not my place.
下一轮我来请吧
Why don't I get the next round?
那么 你还要把你梦寐以求的工作拒绝多少次
So... how many times are you gonna say no to your dream job?
我只是想计划一下我的日程
I'm just trying to plan my day.
我是个胆小鬼
I'm a scaredy-cat, okay?
我想要成为那种
I want to be the type
可以无所畏惧地冲向未知世界的人
of person that just charges fearlessly into the unknown,
但我那次提前两周就从巴黎回来了
but I came back two weeks early from Paris
因为我感到寂寞
because I was lonely.
我去了旧金山
I went to San Francisco,
却经历了我这辈子最糟糕的时光
and I was never more depressed in my life.
我是个小镇人 马修
I'm small town, Marshall.
我是从布鲁克林来的乡下人
I'm a hick from Brooklyn who's terrified of living
连住在离我出生地地铁十站远的地方都害怕
more than ten subway stops from where I was born.
好了 莉莉 如果我能从明尼苏达州圣克劳德
Okay, Lily, if I can move from St. Cloud, Minnesota,
搬到纽约来
to New York City,
你也可以搬到罗马去
then you can move to Rome.
我们一点也不了解意大利
We know nothing about Italy.
在那边一个朋友也没有
We have no friends there.
也不会说意大利语
We don't speak the language.
\N拜托 老兄 别独占所有洋葱圈
好吧 你会说一句
Okay, so you know that one sentence.
你会说别的吗
Can you say anything else?
\N拜托
\N老兄
\N别独占所有洋葱圈
这跟你刚才说的是同一句话
That-that was the same sentence.
只是变了变音调
You just changed the inflection.
\N好吧
拜托
\N你说的对
老兄
\N或许我只会说一句"拜托 老兄 别独占所有洋葱圈"
别独占所有洋葱圈 拜托 老兄 别独占所有洋葱圈
\N但我从心底知道
拜托 老兄
\N我怎么说你都能听懂
别独占所有洋葱圈
\N因为再没有人能如此懂得另一个人
拜托 老兄 别独占所有的
\N比你和我更懂得对方
洋葱圈 拜托 老兄 别独占所有洋葱圈
\N这场旅行真的会很可怕吗
拜托 老兄
\N是的
别独占所有洋葱圈
\N我喜欢待在语言不通的地方吗
拜托 老兄
\N当然不喜欢
别独占所有洋葱圈
\N但我相信我们能做到
拜托 老兄 别独占所有的
\N我爱你 莉莉
洋葱圈 莉莉
\N我爱你
洋葱圈
我也爱你
I love you, too.
好
All right.
我们要去意大利啦
We're going to Italy.
耶
Si!
你可能还不知道 呃
You may not know this yet, but, um,
我已经买了一些装备了
I've already done some shopping.
欢迎回家哟
Welcome home.
喔 你真是太冷艳了
Oh... You are so cool,
但不会冷太久了
but not for long.
HIMYM字幕组 谢谢观看
欢迎关注字幕组新浪微博及人人网主页\N@HIMYM字幕组